<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0"><channel><title><![CDATA[The Personal Website of Brandon Brown]]></title><description><![CDATA[Brandon is a designer and developer focusing his work on creating better systems for education and health.]]></description><link>https://bybrandonbrown.com</link><generator>RSS for Node</generator><lastBuildDate>Wed, 04 Jul 2018 18:09:27 GMT</lastBuildDate><item><title><![CDATA[First Steps Towards Your Best Self Part 3- Eat]]></title><description><![CDATA[This is Part 3 of a small series on how to improve your life
with only a few small changes.
 Read Part 1-Sleep here  and  Read Part 2-Move…]]></description><link>https://bybrandonbrown.com/yourfirststeps-part3/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://bybrandonbrown.com/yourfirststeps-part3/</guid><pubDate>Wed, 04 Jul 2018 12:30:00 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is Part 3 of a small series on how to improve your life
with only a few small changes.
&lt;a href=&quot;../yourfirststeps-part1/&quot;&gt;Read Part 1-Sleep here&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;../yourfirststeps-part2/&quot;&gt;Read Part 2-Move here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Get Up and Move&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now that you’re rested, it’s time to use all of that new found energy. Let’s take a look at where you most likely stand on the activity scale right now. Well, that’s odd, it says you’re sitting.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Did you know that most Americans will walk less than 1 mile per day? Think about this, in roughly 16 hours of conscious time you have managed to not sit at a desk, in a car, or otherwise be stationary for more than 1 mile. Starting to see why your body doesn’t feel great?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Moving is what our bodies are made to do. Everything we have evolved to overcome and specialize in has been in the name of movement. In our modern culture, there isn’t the same impetus as chasing down your family’s next meal while carrying your world on your back.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;It Takes Moves to Solve Problems&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Many of today’s health epidemics, such as obesity and diabetes, are being maximized by stationary lifestyles. Our body relies on movement as an indicator of what systems are necessary, and which can be turned off to allow for efficiencies in other areas. Use it or lose it is the basic rule our bodies run on. You sit all day and have no need to move other than walking to the corner store for lunch? Then let’s reduce the capacity of your lungs, heart, and cardiovascular system. We don’t need it! You don’t have a chance at running into some weird bug, getting cut by a sharp bush, or breaking an ankle on a run? Let’s lower the energy in your immune system, you’re safe right where you are!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Human body is incredible at adapting to the environment surrounding it. Look at how we’ve managed to spread around the world and stay relatively alike. Unlike every other member of the animal kingdom, we didn’t become full-blown specialists. We’re able to adapt, to be the best generalists the earth has ever seen and are thriving for it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We all need to move, your quality of life depends on it. We don’t all need to be athletes or feel the pressure to exercise that social media pushes on many of us. We just need to move. You don’t need a reason. You don’t need a goal. You only need to get moving. Get up and walk for 10 minutes, then come back to this article.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How do you feel? Re-energized? Accomplished? Maybe a little sweaty and sore? Fantastic.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Try 15 minutes tomorrow and take note of how you feel after.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Basic Tactics to get moving more:&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Consistency: Find a time in your day that you feel low on energy, usually reach for a sugar-filled snack or another cup of coffee. Before you think about taking a nap, go for that walk, do ten pushups, maybe find a yoga routine that can get you moving in ways you normally don’t. Whatever you do, stay consistent with your time. Your body is an amazing machine, but it’s also easy to trick. Instead of dreading the afternoon&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Don’t swing for the fences: Start small. Walk a mile before you run a mile. Do basic stretches before you jump into yoga. Stay above water before you start lapping the pool.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Build it in: Fit movement into your busy day. Many people skip the elevator and take the stairs. If you’re able, walk to the local coffee shop in the afternoon instead of reaching for your office or home-brewed cup. Take the kids outside and play a game of soccer with them, but actually play with them!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Get addicted: After every session, no matter how hard, easy, or sweat inducing, tell yourself it was worth it. Mentally train your body to love movement. Be proud of your accomplishments, no matter how big or small they are. They’re your accomplishments to use as fuel to power the next. Your brain is magic, but it can still be tricked.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Hydrate: Drink your water, and lots of it. Don’t reach for sugar-filled juices and sports drinks. Straight, plain-ol’ water is the treat your body wants after any workout. However, there are many studies showing that your body craves minerals after losing them to sweat and energy creation for workouts, so grab some mineral water if you can!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[First Steps Towards Your Best Self Part 2- Move]]></title><description><![CDATA[This is Part 2 of a small series on how to improve your life
with only a few small changes.
 Read Part 1-Sleep here Diet is a Can of Gummy…]]></description><link>https://bybrandonbrown.com/yourfirststeps-part2/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://bybrandonbrown.com/yourfirststeps-part2/</guid><pubDate>Wed, 04 Jul 2018 12:15:00 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is Part 2 of a small series on how to improve your life
with only a few small changes.
&lt;a href=&quot;../yourfirststeps-part1/&quot;&gt;Read Part 1-Sleep here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Diet is a Can of Gummy Worms&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Many people will tell you to follow the diet they did last year because it’s so simple to follow and they saw incredible results. Then they’ll tell you that they’re about to start again because they put all the weight back on after stopping the diet last year.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Well, that doesn’t sound like a healthy solution!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;No More Diets&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Dieting is a bad idea. Dieting isn’t simple, if it were, we’d all be doing the same thing and looking like the perfect specimens of human evolution that we know we could be. If dieting were simple, entire multi-billion dollar industries wouldn’t exist. If we all knew how to eat and stay healthy, do you think there would be pizza delivery to every address in the United States? If we all knew how to consciously choose when to eat sugar, that checkout counters at every grocery store would be lined with sugar snacks? If we could all make these easy diet choices, would we need drugs for cholesterol, high-blood pressure, and all the other problems doctors and pharmacies love to prescribe for?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Dieting isn’t easy. Dieting is tough because many people see it as a short-term solution. “Six-pack abs in 2 weeks!” exclaims a tabloid cover at the checkout-aisle that you’re currently dropping a family-pack of Oreos, frozen pizzas, and a 2-liter of sugar-water on. Then after eating those Oreos and finishing off the pizza the kids didn’t eat, you decide it’s time to get back on your low-carb diet.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Think About Your Food&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Dieting isn’t going to get you to your goals. A healthy lifestyle that weighs the pros and cons of the food you eat, however, will. This is why I chose nutrition as the last topic of the basics to discuss with you. It’s the hardest to understand, the most difficult to follow, and the most guilt-inducing part of the puzzle for nearly everyone looking to make a healthier version of themselves. However, don’t beat yourself up over the Oreo’s. A healthy, nutrition-dense lifestyle is going to take time to develop.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Your nutrition isn’t as easy as what goes in is what comes out. Your nutrition is going to have physiological, timeliness, environmental, social variables, and more to consider. You think Keto sounds great until your friends order a pizza, then it’s your cheat day. You think Paleo sounds great until your friend makes a Peanut Butter and Jelly sandwich, then it’s your cheat day. Your co-workers want to celebrate after work with drinks, so you have a beer with them tonight— and again at the next celebration tomorrow. This is nothing but a cycle of guilt that you have no need to bear the weight of.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Give Yourself a Break&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let’s start simple. Make your home-life as food-temptation free as possible. Start with the easy targets: Cookies, cakes, snacks, sodas, frozen pizzas. When it’s your turn to grocery shop for the family, don’t bring home the cookies.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Your body is that incredible machine we keep talking about. Your brain doesn’t always control your choices, as powerful as you think your mind is. Thinking with your gut is being proven with a lot of powerful research to be more than a saying. Think about the logic for a second: You’ve been feeding your body sugar and other bad-nutrients for years, decades even, and is adapted in a way to run on that fuel. Suddenly, you’ve stopped giving your body the fuel it’s learned to run on. In response, your body powers up all of the cravings and addiction responses it can, trying to manipulate you (you read that right, you’re being unknowingly manipulated by yourself) into giving into the demands of the fuel it wants.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Once you’ve made it through the cravings, you’ll begin to remember what healthy is. Getting pizza at lunch no longer sounds appetizing. No longer are you pushing away guilt, but replacing that feeling with a sense of fulfillment as you know you’ve made a choice better for yourself— and still plenty delicious in the food options!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You go to the grocery store now and don’t even think to go down the cookie aisle. You visit the cereal aisle less- if only to get coffee because the grocery store knows one morning addiction will help to fuel the other. You visit the produce aisle more, you visit the butcher more, you don’t even consider the candy at checkout anymore. All of this from only the small step of not bringing bad food into your home. Next step is eating out and in social situations, but let’s not get ahead of the purpose of this series- the basics.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Basic Tactics for Better Nutrition:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Consistency: Stop dieting. Start making better choices that can last you a lifetime.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Variety: Don’t always buy the same fruit, vegetables, and cuts of meat. Visit different stores. Their produce may be sourced from different regions of the world, giving you a small shift in the variety of nutrients that you otherwise may not be able to obtain.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Think outside the box: If it’s able to sit on a shelf, unrefrigerated, in a box, then think how long it will be able to stay inside your body. This doesn’t apply to everything but is a good basic rule to start thinking twice about the choices you’re making.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Grow your own: Have space for a small garden? Reconnect with your food and grow your own veggies. You’ll learn something along the way, start to appreciate the health of your home-grown foods more, and know exactly what went into growing them.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Trust yourself, train your gut: If you go to pick anything up, and I mean anything, if your brain tells you no, put it back! Your instincts know what is good and what is bad for your body, make your gut listen to your brain. Some food may not taste that great, but you’ll find ways of cooking to improve it, or better yet- your body will learn what real, natural, nutrient-dense food tastes like and start craving these foods again.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Start Simple&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For anything as important as your health, starting simple is the best foundation. You have one body, one chance. You don’t have to live a monk’s life but giving your body the best chances to operate the way it’s meant to will give you the best chances to live the life you want to.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Don’t stress over your macros, don’t worry if your workout split is allowing enough recovery time, don’t get stuck in information paralysis. Fall back on the basics, on your natural foundations, and you’ll be set up to succeed brilliantly in the near future.&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[First Steps Towards Your Best Self Part 1- Sleep]]></title><description><![CDATA[Where to start learning how to live your life to its full potential. Google? Let’s try “How to start working out.” Is learning how to better…]]></description><link>https://bybrandonbrown.com/yourfirststeps-part1/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://bybrandonbrown.com/yourfirststeps-part1/</guid><pubDate>Wed, 04 Jul 2018 12:00:00 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;Where to start learning how to live your life to its full potential. Google? Let’s try “How to start working out.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  &lt;a
    class=&quot;gatsby-resp-image-link&quot;
    href=&quot;/static/googlesearch-e051bbbe1a107c7612b61f139ff1a62a-3920a.jpg&quot;
    style=&quot;display: block&quot;
    target=&quot;_blank&quot;
    rel=&quot;noopener&quot;
  &gt;
  
  &lt;span
    class=&quot;gatsby-resp-image-wrapper&quot;
    style=&quot;position: relative; display: block; ; max-width: 590px; margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto;&quot;
  &gt;
    &lt;span
      class=&quot;gatsby-resp-image-background-image&quot;
      style=&quot;padding-bottom: 25.652841781874038%; position: relative; bottom: 0; left: 0; background-image: url(&apos;data:image/jpeg;base64,/9j/2wBDABALDA4MChAODQ4SERATGCgaGBYWGDEjJR0oOjM9PDkzODdASFxOQERXRTc4UG1RV19iZ2hnPk1xeXBkeFxlZ2P/2wBDARESEhgVGC8aGi9jQjhCY2NjY2NjY2NjY2NjY2NjY2NjY2NjY2NjY2NjY2NjY2NjY2NjY2NjY2NjY2NjY2NjY2P/wgARCAAFABQDASIAAhEBAxEB/8QAFgABAQEAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAIF/8QAFAEBAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAP/aAAwDAQACEAMQAAAB3aAD/8QAFBABAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAEP/aAAgBAQABBQJ//8QAFBEBAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAEP/aAAgBAwEBPwE//8QAFBEBAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAEP/aAAgBAgEBPwE//8QAFBABAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAEP/aAAgBAQAGPwJ//8QAFhAAAwAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAABAR/9oACAEBAAE/IVD/2gAMAwEAAgADAAAAEAAP/8QAFBEBAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAEP/aAAgBAwEBPxA//8QAFBEBAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAEP/aAAgBAgEBPxA//8QAGRAAAwADAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAERQVFx/9oACAEBAAE/EJHciT2dH//Z&apos;); background-size: cover; display: block;&quot;
    &gt;
      &lt;img
        class=&quot;gatsby-resp-image-image&quot;
        style=&quot;width: 100%; height: 100%; margin: 0; vertical-align: middle; position: absolute; top: 0; left: 0; box-shadow: inset 0px 0px 0px 400px white;&quot;
        alt=&quot;Google Search How To Start Working Out&quot;
        title=&quot;&quot;
        src=&quot;/static/googlesearch-e051bbbe1a107c7612b61f139ff1a62a-f8fb9.jpg&quot;
        srcset=&quot;/static/googlesearch-e051bbbe1a107c7612b61f139ff1a62a-e8976.jpg 148w,
/static/googlesearch-e051bbbe1a107c7612b61f139ff1a62a-63df2.jpg 295w,
/static/googlesearch-e051bbbe1a107c7612b61f139ff1a62a-f8fb9.jpg 590w,
/static/googlesearch-e051bbbe1a107c7612b61f139ff1a62a-85e3d.jpg 885w,
/static/googlesearch-e051bbbe1a107c7612b61f139ff1a62a-d1924.jpg 1180w,
/static/googlesearch-e051bbbe1a107c7612b61f139ff1a62a-3920a.jpg 1302w&quot;
        sizes=&quot;(max-width: 590px) 100vw, 590px&quot;
      /&gt;
    &lt;/span&gt;
  &lt;/span&gt;
  
  &lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Is learning how to better yourself really so complicated, that we need to cipher through millions of pieces of results? How do you even know that any of those articles, papers, blog posts, podcasts, or videos will be the right method for you to achieve your goals?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Splits, HIIT, keto, 3x8, push-pull, anabolic, CrossFit- what is all this? Guess you’ll need to pay an expert to help you get started. Maybe the gym down the road can help, but you don’t feel comfortable working out with others. Oh boy, there it is again: Where do you start?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Keep It Simple&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There’s nothing wrong with simple. Simple is effective, quick, understandable, and expandable.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Your health, fitness, and athletic abilities can all be managed, understood, and maximized within three basic pillars: Eat, Sleep, and Move. That’s it. Working to better those three areas is all it takes to level up your health. We’re not going to talk about a diet, we’re not going to talk about sleep patterns, we’re not going to talk about workout routines. All you need to get started is the knowledge that your body wants good nutrition, deep sleep, and to move how it has evolved to over 6 million years.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;To Start, Sleep&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The easiest way to improve your quality of life is to improve the quality of sleep in your life. If you’re waking up feeling groggy, requiring coffee to wake up, or feeling the fog finally lift hours after waking up- you’re in dire need of a sleep fix!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here’s my favorite thing to hear, and to be fair, my younger self was guilty of saying it, too: “I’ll sleep when I’m dead!”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are enough hours in a day for you to get a good, restful sleep and still accomplish everything you can dream of. Sure, there are times in everyone’s life where sleep is sacrificed— You work two jobs, have kids, have a large responsibility to something or someone that cuts into your sleep, but why is it that sleep is the first thing we all think to sacrifice?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sleep is the only chance your body has to properly restore, recover, and repair all of its necessary functions. This includes your mental capabilities, your physical growth, and your overall sense of well being. Proper deep sleep will improve all areas of your life, allowing you more potential growth than downing another can of sugar-filled, carbonated energy ever will.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Basic Tactics for Better Sleep:&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Stay consistent. It’s said to take 28 days to form a habit. Make yourself get in bed, ready to sleep, at the same time every night and your body will respond by giving you better and more effective sleep.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Cut caffeine and other uppers out up to 5 hours before sleep. In fact, try to reduce your caffeine intake overall and watch your energy levels increase!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Dark and Cold will make you sleep long and deep. Think back to the environments our early ancestors evolved through. Before clothes, shelters, and even fire, our bodies responded to the dark and cold of the night by sleeping. Use this evolutionary left-over to trigger a natural deep sleep cycle.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Have a night-time routine. You have enough time to stress about your day to day work and all the other things life can throw your way. Create a routine that can calm your mind and tell your body it’s time to rest.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Declutter. Make your bedroom a sleep sanctuary. Build yourself a hibernation fortress and you will sleep incredibly. Keep your room free of stress reminders such as dirty laundry, used cups, and work-day items. Some people go as far as to remove stressful talk from the bedroom to have nothing but positive and restful associations with their sleep space.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Sleep is Everything&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Without getting control of your sleep, you’re going to be pushing uphill against the weight of low performance across all areas of life. You can’t eat your way out of bad sleep, you can’t run yourself back from bad sleep. Get the rest your body needs and you’ll see improvements across the board. Stress management, sustained energy, increased vitality, muscle growth, and injury prevention all start while you’re asleep. Take your first step towards better health with a good night’s sleep.&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded></item></channel></rss>